Guide to the College Bulletins 1902-1932
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center
College Bulletins
1902-1932
Oregon Agricultural College
PUB 005-11a
0.50 cubic feet 2 boxes and 9 microfilm reels
Special Collections and Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids
The College Bulletins consist of bulletins published by Oregon Agricultural College, and later Oregon State College, to promote the academic programs and outreach activities of the College. Almost 500 bulletins were published over 30 years from 1902 to 1932. Items from this collection have been digitized and are available in Oregon Digital.
Oregon State Agricultural College; Oregon State College.
Oregon Agricultural College--Students.
Agriculture--Study and teaching (Higher)--Oregon--Corvallis.; Agriculture-Vocational guidance.; College students--Oregon--Corvallis.; Military education--Oregon--Corvallis.; Music--Instruction and study--Oregon--Corvallis.; Summer schools--Oregon--Corvallis.; Vocational guidance--Oregon.
Agriculture; Colleges and Universities; Military; Music; Student Life; Women; Oregon; Corvallis
These materials were acquired by the former University Archives from the 1960s through 1990s.
Collection is open for research.
The Illustrated Booklets (PUB 488) consists of College Bulletins that were published by Oregon Agricultural College in the 1910s and 1920s to promote and publicize the College. Some of the College Bulletins are also available in other archival collections, such as the Summer Session Records (RG 270).
The College Bulletins are arranged in 4 series: 1. Individual Unbound Bulletins, 1905-1932; 2. Bound Volumes, 1927-1929; 3. Bound Volumes in OSU History Book Collection, 1902-1932; and 4. Microfilmed Bulletins, 1902-1932. Within series, the bulletins are arranged numerically by bulletin number.
The College Bulletins consist of bulletins published by Oregon Agricultural College, and later Oregon State College, to promote the academic programs and outreach activities of the College. Amost 500 bulletins were published over 30 years from 1902 to 1932 and are available unbound, in bound volumes, and on microfilm.
The Bulletins cover a wide range of topics and include course catalogs, summer session bulletins, reports, announcements and booklets for short courses and other agricultural training, informational booklets for farmers and homemakers, and early youth program project publications. The collection includes booklets that publicize academic programs to future students and promote the full range of activities at the College. Booklets promoting the music education programs at the College are included.
Items from this collection have been digitized and are available in Oregon Digital.
- Individual Unbound Bulletins, 1905-1932; Series 1
  Series 1 consists of about 75 of the published bulletins that are available as unbound issues in this archival collection.
  - 1-59 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Catalogue of the Library of the Oregon Agricultural College, 1905 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Oregon Agricultural College Corvallis, Oregon (Box-folder 1.1)
      Photographic informational book about Oregon Agricultural College in Corvallis Oregon. This item is available online.
    - Oregon Agricultural College Course in Agriculture, 1907-1908 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Oregon Agricultural College Summer School Announcement, 1909 (Box-folder 1.1)
      2 copies
    - The Business Side of Farming Part 1 Farm Records, 1911 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Diseases of Chickens, 1910 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Poultry Contest, 1910 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Road Materials in the Willamette Valley, 1911 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Biennial Report of Eastern Oregon Experiment Station: Union, Oregon, 1911 (Box-folder 1.1)
    - Summer School Oregon Agricultural College Announcements and Courses, 1911 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - 60-99 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Oregon Agricultural College Summer School, Courses and Announcements Illustrated, 1912 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Oregon Agricultural College The Business Side of Farming Part II Practical Problems in Rural Economics, 1894 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Oregon Agricultural College Summer School Session, Courses and Announcements Illustrated, 1913 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Oregon Agricultural College Extension Division Camp Cookery, 1913 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Alumni Directory of Oregon Agricultural College, 1913 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - College Housing of Chickens, 1913 (Box-folder 1.2)
    - Principles of Jelly Making, 1909 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - 100-199 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Feeding Young Chickens, 1909 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Breeds of Chickens, 1914 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - Oregon Agricultural College Summer School, Courses and Announcements Illustrated, 1914 (Box-folder 1.3)
      June 15-July 24
    - Housing of Chickens, 1914 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - 200-299 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - County and Community Fairs, 1909 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Student Expenses (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Short Course: Agriculture for Boys Home Economics for Girls, 1916 (Box-folder 1.4)
      June 19 - June 30
    - Oregon Agricultural College Catalogue of the School of Commerce, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Training for the Home Farm, 1916 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Chemistry and War, 1917 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Engineers and Industrial Expansion, 1917 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Oregon Agricultural College Syllabus Military Business Practice, 1917 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Fill the Breach, 1917 (Box-folder 1.4)
      A call to join the military.
    - College Women and the War, 1918 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Halls of Residence - Rules and Regulations, 1916 (Box-folder 1.4)
    - Inauguration of the Students' Army Training Corps, 1918 (Box-folder 1.4)
      This item is available online.
  - 300-379 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Entrance Information, 1919 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Summer School Session Courses and Announcements, 1919 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - School of Music, 1919 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Training for the Vocations, 1919 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - One-Year Curriculum for Homemakers, 1920 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - After High School- What?, 1920 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - School Of Music, 1920 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - The Home Economics Girl, 1921 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - List of Official Publications of the Oregon Agricultural College, 1922 (Box-folder 1.5)
    - Summer Session Advance Announcement, 1923 (Box-folder 1.5)
      June 18 - July 28 1923
    - The O.A.C. Business Show, 1923 (Box-folder 1.5)
      March 30-31
  - 380-399 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Catalogue of Students 1922-23 Degrees Conferred Honors and Prizes, 1923 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Summer Session, 1923 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - The School of Commerce, 1923 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Oregon State School of Mines, 1923 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - The Booklet of the Summer Session, 1924 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Courses of Instruction, 1924 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Report of Oregon Agricultural Economic Conference, 1924 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Summer Session, 1924 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - The School of Music, 1924 (Box-folder 1.6)
    - Speech Training for Citizenship, 1924 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - 400-439 (Box-folder 2.1)
    - The Booklet of Summer Session, 1924 (Box-folder 2.1)
      Supplement too 400: School for Athlectic Coaches Featuring Knute Rockne and Karl Heckrich, Summer Session June 22-July 31, 1925. The bulletin and the supplement are available online.
    - O.A.C. Educational Exposition, 1924 (Box-folder 2.1)
      Feburary 21-23, 1925. This item is available online.
    - School of Agriculture (Box-folder 2.1)
    - Fifth Annual Canners School, 1925 (Box-folder 2.1)
      Feburary 1 - 19, 1926
    - Summer Session, 1926 (Box-folder 2.1)
    - The New Examination its Construction and Use, 1926 (Box-folder 2.1)
      by the School of Vocational Education
    - The Turn of the Tide, 1927 (Box-folder 2.1)
    - Summer Session, 1927 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - 440-459 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Summer Session, 1928 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Summer Session, 1929 (Box-folder 2.2)
      June 14-July 26 1929
    - College Courses at Oregon State, 1929 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Education in Aeronautics, 1929 (Box-folder 2.2)
      Oregon State School of Engineering
    - Ornamental Trees for Northwest Highways, 1929 (Box-folder 2.2)
      2 Copies
  - 460-483 (Box-folder 2.3)
    - Summer Session, 1930 (Box-folder 2.3)
      June 16-July 25
    - Course and Equipment Organization for Welding, 1930 (Box-folder 2.3)
      Created by Oregon State School of Engineering
    - The Oregon High School Extempore Speaking and Interpretation Contests, 1930 (Box-folder 2.3)
      Published by the State Board of Higher Education.
    - The Booklet of the 1931 Summer Session, 1930 (Box-folder 2.3)
    - Summer Session, 1931 (Box-folder 2.3)
      June 2-July 31
    - Eleventh Annual Canners' School, 1932 (Box-folder 2.3)
      January 25 - February 10
    - Summer Session, 1932 (Box-folder 2.3)
- Bound Volumes, 1927-1929; Series 2
  Series 2 consists of 2 bound volumes described as vocational guidance booklets and handbooks. One of the items, What's What at Oregon State, does not have an assigned bulletin number.
  - Vocational Guidance Booklets, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 2.4)
    This volume includes The Turn of the Tide, 1927 (no 426) about agricultural education; Speech Training and Personality, 1927 (no. 432); and Education in Aeronautics, 1929 (no. 456).
  - Handbooks, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 2.5)
    This volume includes Facts about the College, 1928 (no. 444); College Courses at Oregon State, 1929 (no. 455); The Booklet of the Summer Session, 1927 (no. 431); and What's What at Oregon State, circa 1929.
- Bound Volumes In History of OSU Book Collection, 1902-1932; Series 3
  Series 3 is an item-level description of College Bulletins that are available in bound volumes in the History of OSU Book Collection in the Special Collections and Archives Research Center (HistOSU LD 4337. A2). This item-level list also serves as a list of the bulletins that are available on the microfilm described as Series 4. These bound volumes include posters and other oversize items that are fragile and require careful handling.
  - Volume of Bulletins 1-12
    - Dedication of Agriculture Hall, 1902
    - Story of the Air We Breathe
    - Oregon Junco
    - Agricultural College OAC, Collated from College Catalog
    - The Rocks
    - Short Course Agricultral and Special Dairying
    - Alpha Hall
  - Volume of Bulletins 13-28
    - Course in Forestry
    - Short Course: Agricultural and Special Dairying
    - School of Music
    - Courses of Instruction, 1907-1908
    - Winter Short Courses, 1908
    - Courses of Instructions, 1908-1909
    - School of Domestic Science and Art, 1908-1909
    - Directory of OAC, 1908
    - Winter Short Courses, 1909
    - Winter Short Course in Surveying and Road Construction, 1909
    - Biennial Report of President of the College, 1906-1908
  - Volume of Bulletins 29-42
    - Breeds of Chickens, 1909
    - Housing Chickens, 1909
    - Cordially Invited to Winter Short Courses, 1909
    - Poultry Contest
    - Summer Session Preliminary Annoucement, 1910
    - Incubating Brooding Chickens, 1910
    - Board of Regents, 1908-1909
    - Summer School Announcement, 1910
    - The Quarter Centennial Jubilee
  - Volume of Bulletins 43-58
    - Winter Short Course, 1911
      January 3 - February 17.
    - Annual Report of the President of the Board of Regents, 1909-1910
    - Garden Management
    - Summer School Preliminary Announcement, 1911
    - Garden Managment II, 1911
    - Waldo Hall, 1911
    - Information Regarding Entrance Necessitites for School of Domestic Science and Art, 1911
    - School of Domestic Science and Art; A Suggestive Course, 1911
      Supplement: Winter Short Course January 3 - February 9.
  - Volume of Bulletins 59-69
    - Annual Report of the President of the Board of Regents, 1911
    - Waldo Hall, 1912
    - School of Domestic Science, 1912
    - A Bulletin on Camp Cookery for Special Use of Forest Rangers
      Supplement: Training School of Mines Man for Development of Oregon's Geological Resources
    - Highway Improvement Earth Roads and Culverts
    - Farmers' Week Winter Short Course
    - Winter Short Course, 1913
      January 6 - February 7.
  - Volume of Bulletins 70-76
    - Biennial Report of the Board of Regents
    - Industrial Contests for Oregon Boys and Girls, 1913
    - Summer Session Preliminary Announcement, 1913
  - Volume of Bulletins 77-12
    - Boys Camp School Summer Session, 1913
    - School of Domestic Science and Art Entrance Necessitites
    - Feeding for Eggs, 1913
    - Principles of Bread Making, 1913
    - Principles of Caking Making, 1913
    - List of Bulletins and Other Publications Available for Distribution on Request, 1913
    - Farmers' Week Winter Short Course, 1913
    - The School Luncheon, 1913
    - Herd Record Keeping, 1913
    - Insect Pests of Truck and Garden Crops
    - Some External Parasites of Poultry, 1913
    - Farmers Week, 1913
      Poster
    - Winter Short Courses, 1914
      January 5- 31
    - Winter Short Courses, 1914
      Poster. January 5-31
    - Insects Injurious to Timber
    - Industrial Clubs and Contests for Oregon Boys and Girls; Circular Information, 1914
    - Industrial Clubs and Contests for Oregon Boys and Girls
    - Fowl Tuberculosis
    - Septic Tanks and Absorption Systems
    - Feeding the Dairy Cow, 1914
    - Raising the Dairy Calf
    - Factories Promotion Congress, 1914
      January 14-15
    - List of Bulletins and Other Publications Available for Distribution on Request, 1914
    - Improving the Dairy Herd
    - Farm Butter Making, 1914
    - The Care of Milk and Cream
    - Making the Babcock Test and keeping the Records, 1914
    - Suggested List of Tools and Materials, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Club Work, Enrollment Acknowledgment, 1914
    - Hotbeds and Cold Frames for the Gardener, 1914
    - Sewing-Domestic Science and Art Project
    - Starchy Foods - Domestic Science and Art Project
    - Planning and Planting a Garden, 1914
    - Selecting and Caring for the Flock, 1914
    - Feeding and Care of Dairy Cows, 1914
    - Handling the Fruit Crop, 1914
    - Feeding for Pork and for Show, 1914
    - Mining Engineering as a Profession
    - Growing the Oregon Potato Crop, 1914
    - Questions on Lesson 1 Breeds of Chickens, 1914
    - How and When to Spray the Orchard, 123
    - Corn in Oregon, 1914
    - Treatment of Granular Vaginitis
    - How to Conduct a Fly Campaign
  - Volume of Bulletins 127-161
    - Fruit and Vegetable by-products, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs Corn Growing Project, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs Potato Growing Project, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial clubs Poultry Husbandry Project No. 14, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs Poultry Husbandry Project no. 15
    - Successful Practice for the Easter Oregon Farmer (Dry Farming and Irrigated lands), 1914
    - Sewing: Cotton goods. Domestic Science and Arts Project.
    - Creamed Soups and Vegetables
    - Silo Construction and Silage Feeding
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs. Potato Growing Project Circular 2, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs. Corn Growing Project. Circular 2, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs. Canning and Preserving Project Report
    - Boys and Grils Industrial Clubs. Poultry Raising Project Report., 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs. Sewing Project Report, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs. Pigs Feeding Project Report, 1914
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs. Vegetable Gardenting Project Report.
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs. Baking Project Report, 1914
    - How to Ship Test Samples of Road Material Highway Laboratory Circular, 1914
    - Oregon Station Trap-Nest
    - Boys Short Course in Agriculture, 1914
      June 17-30
    - Domest Science and Art Project: Fruit and Vegetable Canning.
    - Entrace Information, 1914
    - Cultivating and caring for the Garden Vegetable Gardening Project
    - Domestic Science and Art Project: Essentials of Bread Making
    - Breeds and Judging Dairy Cows
    - Feeding for Eggs: Poultry and Husbandry Reading Course Lesson 3
    - Incubating and Brooding Chickens Poultry Husbandry Reading Course
    - Domestic Arts and Science Project: Sewing, 1913-1914
  - Volume of Bulletins 162-199
    - Judging Hogs. Pig Feeding Project
    - Furniture Construction. Manual Arts Project
    - Boys and Girls Industrial Clubs. Circular Letter
    - OAC, A Nationals and State Institution Dedicated to the Work of Enriching Rural Life
    - School Engineering, 1914
    - School Home Economics, 1914
    - Beeking for the Oregon Farmer, 1914
    - The Harvesting and Scoring of Potatoes. Potato Growing Projects
    - The Harvesting and Scoring of Corn. Corn Growing Project
    - Catalogue of the School of Music, 1914-1915
    - How to Candle Eggs
    - List of Bulletins and Other Publications Available for Distribution on Request, 1914
    - Important Events, 1914-1915
    - What Farmers Say, 1914-1915
    - School and Home Gardening for Elementary Schools in Oregon
    - Winter Short Course, 1915
      January 4-30
    - Horse Management
    - Farmers and Home-Makers' Week and Conference Sessions
    - Livestock Management: Beef Cattle
    - Program: Farmers', Homemakers', and Confrence Week at OAC, 1915
      February 1-6
    - Balancing Rations for Dairy Cows, 1915
    - English Walnut Culture
    - Cultural Methods of Important Local Crops in Western Oregon
    - Care and Marketing of Eggs
    - Hog Management and Feeding
    - Marketing of Livestock
    - Feeding Laying Hens
    - Biennial Report Board of Regents, 1915
    - Livestock Management; Swine, 1915
    - Livestock Management; Sheep Raising in Oregon, 1915
    - Stitches, Seams, and sewing Processes
    - Home Econimcs Club; Suggestions for Organizing and Conducting in Oregon
    - The School of Mines
    - The Business Side of Farming. Oregon Laws on Real Property
  - Volume of Bulletins 200-235
    - The Trail Blazers, 1915
    - Information Designed to Aid Operators of the Babcock Test and Users of Babcok Glassware
    - Boys' Summer Camp, 1915
    - Summer School Session manual Training Courses, 1915
    - Boys' Short Course in Agriculture, 1915
      June 16-29
    - Schools and Departments, 1915-1916
    - Catalogue of the School Music
    - The Oregon Breeding Crate
    - The Dipping Vat
    - Breeds of Swine
    - The Self-Feeder for Swine
    - The Farrowing Pen
    - Improve the Oregon Potato Crop; Avoid Diseased Seed
    - Course of Study in Manual Training
    - List of Extension Bulletins available for Distribution on Request, 1915
    - Methods of Cleaning, 1915
    - Farmers and Home-Makers' Week and Rural-Life confrences Winter Short Courses, 1915
    - Announcement of Correspondence Courses, 1915
    - Five Weeks' Graduate Course in Highway Engineering
    - The School Luncheon
    - Program Farmers', homemakers' and Confrence Week, 1916
    - Program of Winter Short Course, 1916
    - Industrial Arts Courses, Summer School Session, 1916
    - The Elm Leaf-Beetle, 1916
    - Scope of the College Course, 1916
    - Orchard Spraying in Oregon, 1916
    - The Student's Opportunity at OAC Opportunities for Men
    - Student Life at OAC Folder
    - The Student's Opporortunity at OAC II Opportunities for Women, 231
    - Student Traditions and Athletic Ideals
    - Summer School Session Courses and Announcements, 1916
  - Volume of Bulletins 236-264
    - Catalogue of the School of Music, 1916-1917
    - Halls of Residence; Rules and Regulations, 1916
    - Department of Pharmacy, 1916
    - Catalogue of the School Forestry, 1916-1917
    - Letter to OAC Students, 1916
    - Exhibits of OAC at the 1916 State Fair
    - The School of Home Economics
    - Announcement of Five Weeks' Graduate Course in Highway Engineering, 1916
    - Second Semester Registrations, 1916
    - Schools and Departments, 1916
    - 1917 Program of Winter Short Course, 1916
    - Biennial Report of the Board of Regents,1914-1916
    - Field Work at OAC Folder, 1917
    - OAC Summer School, 1916
    - Catalogue of the School of Commerce, 1917-1918
    - Summer School Session Courses and Announcements, 1917
    - The School of Commerce, 1917
    - Called to the Colors, 1917
    - Facts about the OAC, 1917
    - Catalogue of the School of Music, 1917-1918
    - Halls of Residence Rules and Regulations, 1917
    - School of Pharmacy, 1917
  - Volume of Bulletins 265-290
    - Catalogue of the School of Forestry, 1917-1918
    - The Student and the War, 1917
    - Personal Hygiene, 1917
    - Military Science Lectures, 1917
    - New Horticultural Products Course, 1917
    - Second Semester Registration, 1917
    - New Horticultural Products Course
    - 1918 Program of Winter Short Course, 1917
      January 7 - February 1
    - Compilation of useful Military Information, 1918
    - Training in Team Work, 1918
    - College Training and Cash, 1918
    - Summer School session Courses and Annnouncements, 1918
    - New Degree Course in Chemical Engineering, 1918
    - Centeral Officers' Training Schools for Candidates for Comissions in the Infantry, 1918
    - Young Patriots, Enlish in College!, 1918
    - Catalogue of the Oregon Agricultural College, 1918
    - War Training and Military Units of the OAC, 1918
    - School of Pharmacy, 1918
    - Student Army Training Corps, 1918
    - Types of Military Training at the OAC, 1918
    - Students Army Training Corps, 1918
    - Supplement. Central Officers' Training School Folder, 1918
  - Volume of Bulletins 291-320
    - Vocational and Special Courses for Class B Men, 1918
    - Education for Enlisted Men, 1918
    - Biennial Report of the Board of Regents, 1916-1918
    - Courses in Home Economics, Summer Session, 1919
    - Summer School Courses in Physical Education, 1919
    - Hall of Residence; rules and regulations, 1919
    - Leadership, 1919
    - Summer School Course in Military Training, 1919
    - Entrance Information, 1919
    - School of Pharmacy, 1919
    - School of Music, 1919
    - School of Pharmacy
    - State Financial Aid for Soliders, Sailors, and Marines
    - Courses of Study, 1919
    - Men's Dormitory, 1919
    - Winter Short Courses, 1919
  - Volume of Bulletins 321-351
    - Training for the Vocations; Mining Engineering, Chemical Engineering, 1920
    - Study the Facts About OAC, 1920
    - Preliminary Announcement, Summer session, 1920
      June 21 - July 31
    - Summer School Session Courses and Annoucements, 1920
    - Training for Extension Work, A Course in Extension methods in OAC, 1920
    - Department of Physical Education, Summer Session, 1920
    - Halls of Residence for Women: Rules and Regulations, 1920
    - Military Instruction at OAC, 1920
    - Recitation Schedule, Summer Session, 1920
    - School of Pharmacy, 1920
    - The Men's Dormitory; Rules and Regulations, 1920
    - Dairy Manufacturers Short Course, 1920
    - Short Courses for Tractors and Farm Mechanics, 1920
    - Summer Session Advance Announcment
      Junes 20 - July 30
    - Announcing Cash Scholarship Gifts to Graduates of Oregon High School, 1920
    - Contest Number 1 in the cash scholarship gift contest between graduates of Oregon, 1920
    - Contest Number 2 in the Oregon Agricultural College Cash Gift, 1920
    - Preliminary Announcement Summer Session, 1920
    - General Information, 1920
    - School of Agricultural Supplement Farmers' Week
    - School of Commerce, 1921
    - School of Engineering and Mechanic Arts, 1921
    - School of Forestry, 1921
    - School of Home Economics, 1921
    - School of Mines
    - School of Pharmacy, 1921